V.CHINNADURAI

QUALITY CONTROL

Phone: 9597819673

E-Mail: chinnadurai.52@gmail.com



CAREER OBJECTIVE

To bring to an established corporation - enthusiasm, dedication, responsibility and excellent work ethic combined with a desire to utilize the skills obtained through my experience from leading results-driven training, project management, product testing, and quality assurance as an accomplished Quality Manager.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Well versed ISO 9001:2015, IATF 16949, and OHSAS 19001, SAP, Jishu Kozien, Kaizen, FMEA, 7 QC tools, PPAP, APQP, HOQ, QMS, MSA, Quality Audit, PSA, Bench marking, SIX SIGMA.PARETO, Analysis, 8D, CAPA, DFMEA, PFMEA, Process Capabality, CMM,

RESPONSIBILITIES

- > Monitoring the production line and doing periodic Quality Control checks
- > Implementing improvements to production processes that lead to overall increases in product quality
- Working together with project leaders to discuss solutions to quality issues Satisfying customer expectations about the product's quality
- > Creating production plans for new products to guarantee quality from stage one Scheduling project plans along with the project team to fitproject deadlines
- > Writing reports on design, pre-production, and production to check on the quality status of the product at all stages of production and inform the rest of the production team
- > Complying with ISO accreditation requirements
- Auditing materials provided by suppliers to assure quality before incorporation into the product
- Assessing the product's quality by testing for arange of features and seeing how the product performs under stresses like impact, temperature, humidity, etc.
- Investigating causes of quality problems and proposing solutions Training new Quality Control employees
- ➤ Utilizing extensive knowledge of the product's inner workings to diagnose problems Continuing education on newly developing Quality Control techniques

WORK EXPERIENCE

Company : **Jupiter Enterprises**

MIDC Area, Thane Road, Navi Mumbai

Designation : Machine Operator

Reported to: Mr. Magesh Kumar, Manager

Period : 2001 - 2003 (2 years)

Company : A-Win Enterprises

144, Kumaran Nagar, Ambatur, Chennai

Designation : Machine Operator & Line Inspector

Reported to: Mr. Magesh Kumar, Manager

Period : 2003 - 2006 (3 years)

Company : TVS Sundaram Clayton, Hosur

Designation : GET QAD

Product : Tata Nano Cylinder Head

Reported to: Sri.Prasanna Kumar, Assistant Manager

Period : 4 Aug 2009 - 5 Jan 2010 (6 months)

Company : **RS Prateeksha Engineering**, Chennai

Designation : Senior Quality Engineer

Period : *March 2013 - June 2020 (7 years)*

ABOUT ME

Father : Vadivel (Farmer)

Mother : Samuthirakani

DOB : 07/05/1980

Religion : Saivam, Hindu

Nationality : Indian

LANGUAGES

Tamil, English, Hindi, Malayalam, Telugu, Chinese (Beginner) Arabic (Beginner)

INTERESTS

Yoga, Pranayama, Yogashanas, Meditation

Current CTC : 55,000 pm

.....

Exptected CTC: 65,000 pm

Notice Period : 30 Days

Current Location: Chennai

Availability for Interview

Anytime

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

SI.no.	Course	Name of the Institution	Board	Year	Score
1	SSLC	Cathedral Higher Secondary School, Palayamkottai, Tirunelveli	State Board of Tamil Nadu	1995	72
2	HSLC	Kamaraj Municipal Secondary School, Pettai, Tirunelveli	State Board of Tamil Nadu	1997	50
3	DME (MECH)	Nilgiri Plant Association Centenery Polytechnic College, Kotagiri	Technical Education Board of Tamil Nadu	2001	81
4	BE (MECH)	Infant Jesus College of Engineering, Thoothukudi	Anna University Chennai	2009	70
5	ME (MANU)	Satyam College of Engineering and Technology, Arazhvaimozhi	Anna University Chennai	2017	80

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date: / /2022

Place: Thoothukudi CHINNADURAI.V